Masaki!
I'm sorry!
You killed Eisuke Tsuji, didn't you?
That's why
that accident…
Kaori was…
My father was involved as a prosecutor
in the environmental energy
corruption case.
I have to say it was a bit lousy
as a prosecutor.
Mr. Nogi is a former prosecutor.
He was my father's colleague?
Will you marry me?
Yes. I'd be happy to marry you.
Some nerve showing up, Masaki.
-I should leave now.
-Huh?
What do you actually know, Masaki?
I want to know too.
I knew I must not go.
I knew I shouldn't, but…
I'm sorry.
Forget that.
It's impossible.
Then…
don't forget it.
Whenever I see Kanade,
I can't hide my feelings.
What was I hoping to achieve
by coming back?
It was the same when I was a kid.
I never felt like I belonged.
The very first memory I have
is from the end of the summer
when I was three years old.
My mother told me
to wait there for a while.
And
she never came back.
Later, I was somehow under a tree
looking at a dead cicada.
It might have been from that day
that I had a fear of loving anyone.
Even after my mother left,
he was so busy with work,
he barely had any time to spend with me.
I came to realize
I was born into a prominent family
in Yokohama.
It didn't matter to me.
It didn't matter to me at all.
That's what I thought.
Masaki, come here.
He remarried,
and my new mother
tried very hard to get me to like her.
I hated it, so I was rebellious.
Look at the camera, please.
Here we go.
FAMILY PORTRAIT
They forced me to attend the school
where he had graduated.
Why can't you come to class
like everyone else?
But I disobeyed the teacher
and cut class all the time.
I've done my share of bad things.
Want to go to the arcade?
Are you listening? Hey, let's go.
But…
I've heard my son Masaki
has been causing trouble.
-I apologize.
-It's quite all right.
No matter what I did,
he sorted out any problems.
That made me rebel even more.
I was childish.
SHINANO UNIVERSITY
The reason I went to a rural university
was to get away from my family.
But I chose law as my major.
Join our tennis club. Everyone's welcome.
There was an unspoken pressure.
I was unable to escape
from his influence.
We're the cinema studies club.
Come join us.
Right after classes started,
an obnoxious guy spoke to me.
You're Nogi, right?
Yeah.
I'm Yuki Umeda. Where are you from?
-Yokohama.
-Wow!
I'm from Kawasaki!
Doesn't this place feel so rural?
Not a whiff of urban-ness.
He was so unguarded.
At first, I suspected he had
an ulterior motive.
-But…
-I'm hungry but I'm broke!
-I can't buy lunch.
-This is all I have too.
-I guess we should share.
-Okay.
-Let's see.
-I want curry.
-I want fried rice.
-Let's have curry.
Wait, this is better.
DONATION BOX FOR HUNGRY CHILDREN
AROUND THE WORLD
Huh?
He was truly generous.
Pretty please! Let me borrow
your notes for the test.
-Come on.
-No. You were in the class.
It's not for me though.
-It's for Masaki.
-Heh heh.
Don't try to be cute.
Why don't you ask me yourself then?
Tomo, let's have lunch.
And while you're at it help me study.
Everyone comes to me before an exam.
-Come on, Tomo.
Then it's settled. Let's go.
Are you kidding me?
The girls were carefree friends.
Tomo and Kaori.
Then I met Kanade.
Show me your answers, so, I, can, cheat.
-The windshield wipers stopped.
-If we die, we die together.
No way! I don't want to.
I really don't want to die.
Then, how did you know about this place?
Just by chance.
You even turned off the headlights--
Kanade.
I love you.
It was the first time
I ever loved somebody from the heart.
-I'm never letting you go.
-I feel the same.
I don't know exactly
what attracted me to Kanade.
When someone who you thought loved you
suddenly disappears,
it hurts. I know.
But I felt that she and I were similar.
Those were fun days.
But…
I ruined it.
Quit fooling around!
Because…
Kanade's dad was--
Don't say it!
I ruined everything.
NOGI
Honey, can you drive Risa?
Yes I can.
Thanks. Hurry up, Risa.
I wondered how many years it had been
since I saw my sister.
We have time so it should be fine.
-Take care.
-Okay.
They look like a happy family
when I'm not included.
Goodbye.
But behind that happiness,
there are those who were sacrificed.
My stepmother and my sister
don't know the truth.
My relationship with Masaki
was a thing of the past.
I told myself that.
Now I have finally obtained happiness.
And yet
Kaori's accident was on my mind.
Aren't you going to eat?
I'll be right there.
You want to buy a condo?
Don't you think this place is too small
for a married couple?
Some day it might be.
Yeah?
I did some checking and there are
good places available nearby.
Something wrong?
Well, what if I get transferred
to another city?
I think there's definitely going to be
more moving around for me.
How do you feel about it?
Shouldn't we think about those things
as they come up?
It's not that complicated.
I guess you're right…
But for me, it's an important
decision to make.
Oh, I have to go.
I'm done eating.
Thanks.
-Hey.
-Hmm?
Have you thought about quitting your job
and becoming a lawyer instead?
If you did, we wouldn't have to worry
about being apart, right?
Of course, it's up to you.
Oh, I really have to go.
Have a nice day.
At that moment,
I realized for the first time
what Takashi was hoping for.
Have I ever thought about
quitting my job as a prosecutor?
Yes.
Never. Not once.
I see…
-Never?
-Yes.
Everyone around me became my enemy.
My colleagues, my boss.
My husband.
Did your doctor-boyfriend
tell you to quit?
Um, no.
That's when everyone hesitates.
Prosecutors can't avoid transfers.
Marriage, childbirth, parenting…
Should you stay a prosecutor
and be transferred by yourself,
or just quit and become a lawyer?
Maybe quit working altogether?
But you know, in my opinion,
somebody who's not fully a prosecutor
doesn't have the right to waver.
If you're not sure,
you might as well quit.
Your level of commitment is low anyway.
You might be happier that way.
Although I think,
what happiness consists of
depends entirely on that person.
As she said,
I might not have been
a full-fledged prosecutor
and didn't have a right to waver.
But still,
I didn't want to quit this job.
Besides, I still had
something I had to do.
This accident…
Do you suppose it was a crime?
I'm the one who…
RECENTS
TAKASHI, TOMO
If I find out something,
can I contact you?
I want to talk about something.
Me too.
I wanted to ask you something.
Come in.
Is this allowed?
Not really.
But no one can hear us in here.
Kanade.
I see you're a prosecutor for real.
Huh?
You even have your own office.
Yeah.
What did you want to talk to me about?
Oh, here.
Vanilla ice cream.
Since I promised
I'd get it for you.
Where are you going?
I got a call from a girl.
Just kidding. To the store.
Then buy some ice cream.
Is vanilla okay?
I'll tell you…
about that day.
This feels…
like an interrogation.
It should.
I need to hear your story.
Unless you tell me,
I can't move forward.
I…
I can't be done.
Why…
Why were your fingerprints
found on the steering wheel
when they checked Kaori's car?
I see.
On that day…
Yes.
I was awakened
by Kaori calling me.
Hello?
I knew you would come.
Get in.
Just get in.
I got in Kaori's car.
And she said that
I shouldn't be dating you.
And that your dad
didn't commit suicide.
Kanade's dad didn't commit suicide.
He was murdered.
What?
Kaori said that?
So
I made her stop the car
and I let her talk.
She told me about the case
your dad and my father were involved in.
"The corruption case involving the subsidy
of environmental energy."
Your father became famous
because of this case.
But Kanade's dad
took his own life after the case.
What do you mean?
What are you saying?
This case seems strange to me.
The politician who was arrested
was guilty for sure,
but in the trial,
everything was overturned.
Kanade's dad was forced
to take responsibility.
Kaori seemed to be
suspecting something.
At the trial,
who overturned all the testimony
and evidence?
It was your father.
After losing the trial, Kanade's dad
was accused of a crime.
And then
he died.
Hey.
Your dad used to be
a prosecutor, wasn't he?
Did you know that he was
a colleague of Kanade's dad?
No, I didn't.
I heard the two were rivals.
So what?
Are you saying he did something?
Kaori?
I know
because I went to see your father
and heard everything.
She went to see my dad.
Who said she could?
I lost it.
I totally lost my cool.
What the hell…
What are you doing?!
Like I said!
You shouldn't be seeing Kanade!
Why?!
Hey.
Do you want to die with me?
Huh?
Let's die together.
Kaori started the car suddenly.
She drove dangerously fast.
Kaori!
Why can't I ever get what I want the most?
Come on, stop! This is nuts!
Why won't you believe me?!
She had been acting weird
around that time.
I thought our lives were in danger.
So I grabbed the wheel,
and I tried like hell to stop her.
Kaori!
But…
she had remarkable strength.
Kaori!
Stop! I'm serious!
Stop!
I thought she was really trying to die.
I said stop!
She could be so dumb.
I was frantically telling her
to stop the car.
Stop!
Kaori!
And then?
Then before I knew it,
Kaori… turned the wheel.
You're saying
Kaori was the one
who turned the wheel?
Are you sure?
I…
I let go of the wheel.
Then…
why did you say something like that?
I'm sorry!
I'm the one who…
killed Kaori.
Because it was the same
as if I'd done it.
Why wasn't I…
able to listen to her more calmly?
Why couldn't I…
make her relax?
I could have gotten her a soda float
and said,
"You're cute, Kaori"
or something like that.
Like I always do.
But the truth is
I was tired…
of being pushed around
by Kaori.
Somewhere in my mind,
I'd had enough of her antics.
I did get pissed off
when she talked about my dad.
But that wasn't all.
I was thinking
"I love Kanade."
"So?"
"What's wrong with that?"
And I think…
I was also scared of dying.
That's why I let go of the steering wheel.
After the accident,
he came to the hospital.
The police determined the accident
was due to Kaori's negligence.
I was a suspect but as always,
he made it go away.
But…
I fled.
When I was told the accident
was Kaori's fault, I didn't deny it.
So…
it's as if I killed her.
Why did you…
disappear without telling anybody?
I didn't know…
how I could face you guys.
I knew that
we wouldn't ever see Kaori again,
and it was my fault.
Are you going to be okay?
Will you be able to sleep in the tent?
No problem!
I'm going now. Bye.
Have fun.
You're saying
Kaori was the one who texted
and asked you to come out.
And it was her who was driving too fast.
That's what happened.
No.
I couldn't stop her.
It was my fault.
I ran away after that
without saying a word.
I just ran.
Tomo has every right to scold me.
Tomo.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
You're wrong.
It's not Maski's fault.
It's my fault.
Tomo?
I'm the one
who told Kaori about the corruption case.
What?
I'm sorry, Kanade.
Masaki.
Around that time,
my graduation thesis
was on cases of false accusations.
THE MECHANISM
OF FALSE ACCUSATION CASES
I found an article on the corruption case.
ENVIRONMENTAL ENERGY CORRUPTION CASE
EISUKE TSUJI SUSPECTED
OF FALSIFYING EVIDENCE
He was a public prosecutor in Tokyo.
He left my mother and me
and took his own life.
COMMITS SUICIDE AT HOME
The prosecutor in charge
was… Kanade's father.
And I learned that the attorney
who uncovered it was Masaki's father.
I was so surprised, I just…
told Kaori about it without thinking.
What? You're kidding.
Oh my…
I-I was shocked
when I learned about it too.
Look at this.
ENVIRONMENTAL ENERGY CORRUPTION CASE
REACHES CLIMAX AFTER FOURTH TRIAL
This is bad.
Don't you think so?
Then Kaori's actions escalated, and…
Don't do something like that.
That's going too far.
But you're the one who told me
how bad it would be if this were true.
-Yes, but--
-You knew he was going out with her.
That's why you thought it was no good.
Kaori, hold on--
You thought he should know too.
I realize I shouldn't have
told you about it.
But even if it were true,
it's their problem and not ours.
We don't have the right to step in.
What good will it do, anyway?
You're being argumentative again.
I know that you like Masaki.
But that doesn't mean--
I don't have feelings for Masaki.
Not at all.
I'm just saying it because he's a friend.
Hey, stop. I can't take all this
schoolgirl-level talk anymore.
Leave me out of it.
My life depends on my studies.
Then why did you show me this?
You encouraged me, Tomo.
That's not fair.
Kaori said
she went to Masaki's father's office
and asked him questions.
I couldn't believe what she was doing.
I couldn't take her seriously.
So I snapped and said…
I went all the way
to Tokyo to see him. But you--
You did? To ask him for a job?
How could you?
How can a friend say such a thing?
That's cruel, Tomo!
You…
Kaori was crying.
But I was still mad at her.
I didn't even run after her.
Considering her personality,
I should have known.
But who knew she would die?
Who knew it'd be the last time?
That's why…
whenever I think about Kaori,
I always remember what I did.
So I tried hard not to think about it,
and desperately sealed off my memory, but…
It's not your fault, Tomo.
It's not.
No, I did it.
It's my fault.
It was me who…
Tomo.
It was me.
Both Tomo
and Masaki
were still living under the weight
of Kaori's death.
It was a pain that hadn't healed
and still continues now.
The days of our youth
continued after that day.
They hadn't ended yet,
even though we'd become 35 years old.
Hey, do you want to keep walking
a little bit more?
I don't feel like going home right now.
Are you okay being with me?
Sure.
You're my friend
from my university days, right?
Remember what Kaori said
while looking very serious?
Let's be friends forever.
Don't mock our… friendship!
And everyone laughed.
Yeah.
But she was not kidding.
I'll forget about that kiss, okay?
You knew?
Mm-hmm.
You did?
Yeah.
Because when you had that fight…
Were you listening?
Huh?
No.
Your voices were so loud,
it was impossible not to hear.
I knew that Kaori's death
was on your mind a lot too.
That's why you went out with me on a whim,
got pregnant with Nozomi,
and married me.
You even gave up
on your dream of passing the bar exam.
It's not that I gave up.
It's not like that.
Huh?
I felt like Nozomi
was the reincarnation of Kaori.
-Reincarnation?
-Yeah.
A precious life was given to me.
I wanted to cherish it.
You know,
I wouldn't be here
if you weren't there for me back then.
Thank you, Yuki.
It's nothing, because…
I've always liked you.
From the first time I met you.
What?
I didn't know that.
I thought you probably didn't.
Tomo!
I promise…
to try my best.
For you,
and for Nozomi.
So…
let's keep living
our lives together, okay?
Huh?
I can get home on my own from here.
Thank you.
Okay.
Where do you live now, Masaki?
Nowhere, I just stay in various places.
I'm going far away soon anyway.
Overseas again?
Yeah.
Kanade.
About my dad.
I'm thinking of going to see him again
and asking questions.
What?
If he framed your father in some way,
I'll never forgive him.
He's the type who would do such a thing.
To win a trial
he would do anything.
-So--
-Wait.
I'll do the investigation.
Huh?
Because we're not sure of anything yet.
But Kaori told me back then…
We don't know the truth yet.
What did your father say to Kaori
when she met him?
Why did she tell you
my father had been murdered?
What was hidden behind the case
they were working on?
Why did my father die?
There's no absolute proof.
Knowing about my father
is very important to me too.
Besides…
I shouldn't blindly doubt someone.
He's your father after all.
I see you have become
a prosecutor for real.
You're right.
That's what I am.
You can't see any stars here.
I see one.
That doesn't count.
Just as I promised Masaki,
I found time during work
to investigate my father's case further.
JUDICIAL POLICE OFFICER
KUNIMITSU NOZAWA
I tried to question people
who were involved in the case, but…
This is Nishimura.
May I speak with Mr. Aoki the attorney?
My name is Nishimura
from the Yokohama District Office.
Is Mr. Takezawa there?
Nagoya District Office?
My name is Nishimura
from the Yokohama District Office.
Nobody was willing to talk to me.
Time went by without any results.
Kana Kana, come here.
Daddy's job is to be committed
to what I believe is justice.
Do you feel any pain or swelling?
No.
How about here?
A little.
All right.
How's your overall condition? Any fatigue?
Not particularly.
You said you first felt something was off
when you were overseas.
Did you get the same diagnosis?
Yes.
They said I had gallbladder cancer.
When the name of a juvenile criminal
is made public,
losing the opportunity for correction
may be a human rights violation.
We must be careful not to obstruct
the healthy growth and correction…
Are you Mr. Yuki Umeda
from the Atore law firm?
Uh, yes.
Do you have a minute to talk?
How should we proceed with your treatment?
If you're staying around here for a while,
it's possible for you
to receive treatment at this hospital.
Let me think about it.
I see.
If you're starting treatment,
I think the sooner the better.
I understand.
By the way, this might sound strange but
did you attend Shinano University?
Yes, I did.
Actually, I went there too.
So did my fiancée.
Really?
Yes.
My fiancée's name is Kanade Nishimura.
It looks like you've decided
to stay on as a prosecutor.
Try meeting this person.
He should know the most about your father.
RYUICHI NIIZATO
-Are you Mr. Niizato?
-Yes.
I'm Kanade Nishimura.
I'm the daughter of Eisuke Tsuji.
My, you've become quite impressive.
You might not remember,
but we've met a few times
before your father's death
and after as well.
Oh, I didn't know.
I appreciate your help.
Did you happen to meet
the daughter of Eisuke Tsuji recently?
Subtitle translation by: Ikuko Sachs
He died to prevent
the truth from coming out.
It can't end this way!
What's the matter with you?
This was clearly done
by an out-of-control prosecution.
-We need to talk.
-Come in.
Goodbye, Kanade.
I…
Our destiny.